Guide to the William S. Burroughs Papers MSS.625
Fales Library and Special Collections
William S. Burroughs Papers
1749-2012
1981-1997
Fales Library and Special Collections
Burroughs, William S., 1914-1997
The Wylie Agency LLC
Grauerholz, James
MSS.625
25.63 Linear Feet in 52 manuscript boxes, 1 cassette box, 1 flat file folder, 2 shared card boxes, and 4 folders in 2 shared flat boxes
4.47 Megabytes in 446 computer files
12 audiocassettes
William S. Burroughs (1914-1997) was an American writer and visual artist primarily associated with postmodernism and the Beat Generation subculture. He wrote 18 novels and novellas, six collections of short stories, four collections of essays, and five books have been published of his interviews and correspondences. Burroughs also collaborated on projects and recordings with numerous performers and musicians, made many appearances in films, and created and exhibited thousands of visual artworks, including his celebrated "Shotgun Art." Burroughs' semiautobiographical writing often addressed themes of substance use, homosexuality, mysticism, and death, and frequently employed experimental prose and unreliable narrators. The William S. Burroughs Papers (bulk 1981-1997) consist of materials documenting Burroughs' personal and professional life as a novelist and short story writer. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence and manuscripts in various stages of completion. Notable correspondents include Paul Bowles, Lucien Carr, Gregory Corso, Allen Ginsberg, Ted Morgan, David Ohle, and Patti Smith. Works documented in this collection include The Black Rider: The Casting of the Magic Bullets (a musical fable created with Tom Waits and Robert Wilson, 1989), My Education: A Book of Dreams (1995), the editorial selection The Letters of William S. Burroughs, Vol. 1: 1945-1959 (1993), as well as shorter works, including "Death Fiend Guerrillas", Ghost of Chance, "The Johnson Family", and Tornado Alley. The materials document not only Burroughs' artistic process, but also the larger context of postmodern literature and the Beat Generation subculture.
Scope and Contents
The William S. Burroughs Papers (bulk 1981-1997) consist of materials documenting Burroughs' personal and professional life as a novelist and short story writer. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence and manuscripts in various stages of completion. Notable correspondents include Paul Bowles, Lucien Carr, Gregory Corso, Allen Ginsberg, Ted Morgan, David Ohle, and Patti Smith. Works documented in this collection include The Black Rider: The Casting of the Magic Bullets (a musical fable created with Tom Waits and Robert Wilson, 1989), My Education: A Book of Dreams (1995), the editorial selection The Letters of William S. Burroughs, Vol. 1: 1945-1959 (1993), as well as shorter works, including "Death Fiend Guerrillas", Ghost of Chance, "The Johnson Family", and Tornado Alley. However, there is not a significant amount of material for Burroughs' more well-known works, such as Naked Lunch and other novels. The materials document not only Burroughs' artistic process, but also the larger context of postmodern literature and the Beat Generation subculture. Many of the folders are decorated, but materials documenting Burroughs' career as a visual artist are not a significant part of this collection. Burroughs' frequent use of the themes of substance use, homosexuality, and death, as well as his general interests in firearms, animals, and the occult, are well documented in the collection through his subject files. Additional autobiographical material is provided by a few personal items, including psychiatric evaluations, a series of letters with his doctors, photographs, and an employee's lawsuit regarding unpaid wages. Additional collaborative work is evident through event posters and flyers, materials related to his participation in a video by the band U2, and materials related to Literary Outlaw: The Life and Times of William S. Burroughs by Ted Morgan.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged into six series, one of which has been further arranged into subseries. The series and subseries arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Personal
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Writing
Subseries III.A. The Black Rider: The Casting of the Magic Bullet
Subseries III.B. Everything Lost: The Latin American Notebook of William S. Burroughs
Subseries III.C. The Letters of William S. Burroughs, Vol. 1: 1945-1959
Subseries III.D. My Education: A Book of Dreams
Subseries III.E. Novels
Subseries III.F. Short Stories and Novellas
Subseries III.G. Unpublished and Unrealized Projects
Series IV. Artwork
Series V. Events and Publicity
Series VI. Subject Files
All series and subseries are arranged alphabetically.
Appraisal
One letter and envelope from Allen Ginsberg to William S. Burroughs with evidence of mold were photocopied, and the originals discarded. A tablecloth, scarf, and personal items of James Grauerholz were removed and returned to the donor.
Biographical Note
William S. Burroughs (1914-1997) was an American writer and visual artist primarily associated with postmodernism and the Beat Generation subculture. He wrote 18 novels and novellas, six collections of short stories, four collections of essays, and five books have been published of his interviews and correspondences. Burroughs also collaborated on projects and recordings with numerous performers and musicians, made many appearances in films, and created and exhibited thousands of visual artworks, including his celebrated "Shotgun Art." Burroughs' semiautobiographical writing often addressed themes of substance use, homosexuality, mysticism, and death, and frequently employed experimental prose and unreliable narrators.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James Grauerholz via The Wylie Agency in June 2021, and transferred to NYU Special Collections in December 2022. The accession number associated with this purchase is 2023.004.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library and Special Collections, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Related Materials
Additional archival collections on William Burroughs are held at the Henry W. and Albert A. Berg Collection of English and American Literature at the New York Public Library, Columbia University's Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Ohio State University's Rare Books and Manuscript Library, and Emory University Libraries.
Authors, American.; Beats (Persons); American literature.; Postmodernism (Literature); The Wylie Agency LLC; Grauerholz, James; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997
- Series I. Personal, 1940-1997; 0.44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of materials related to Burroughs' personal life. Materials, which reflect his day to day life, include psychiatric evaluations, correspondence with doctors, a lawsuit from a former employee for unpaid wages, a bill for firearms, photographs, itineraries, a Scientology routine, and a card for a narcotics dependence program.
  - Authors Guild Membership, 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bill of Sale for Firearms, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bradley H. Koehler v. William Burroughs Communications, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cats, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Itineraries and Daily Planners, 1983-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Narcotic Dependence and Methadone Programs, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1977-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Psychiatric Evaluations and Correspondence with Doctors, 1940-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
  - Reading Lists, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Resume, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Scientology Routines with Antony Balch, circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II. Correspondence, 1962-2012; 12.99 Linear Feet in 25 manuscript boxes, 1 cassette box, 1 oversize folder, and 2 folders in 2 shared flat boxes; 1 audiocassette
  This series consists of letters, writing, press, and in some cases, artwork, with various correspondents, both personal and professional. Some files contain more publicity and less direct correspondence, as with Jean-Michel Basquiat, whose file includes an exhibition annoucement, and Andy Warhol, whose file includes his memorial program. Additionally, there is general correspondence, consisting of fan mail, requests for interviews, and publisher requests for feedback and reviews. These materials illustrate Burroughs' interest in maintaining numerous personal relationshsips and connections to his readers.
  - Abrams, Terry, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Acker, Kathy, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Aldrich, Fred, 1982-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Allen, John -- Biosphere 2, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1983-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Film Institute, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ames, Jack, 1986-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Anderson, Andy, 1982-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Heidi -- Re: David Budd's Memorial, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Andrews, George, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Andrews, Lynn, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Anger, Kenneth, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ansen, Alan, 1962-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Aronowitz, Al, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ayers, David, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Babbs, O.B., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bachardy, Don, 1986-1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Balance, John (a.k.a. Geff Rushton), 1985-1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Balch, Antony, 1963-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Ball, Gordon, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Baraka, Amiri and Amina, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Barelli, Susan, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Basquiat, Jean-Michel, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bassett, John, 1982-1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Baudron, Isabelle and Jean-Louis, 1983-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Baur, Joan, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Beal, Dana, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Beiles, Sinclair, 1986-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Belli, Bill, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Belue, Otto, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Benz, Obie, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Berkson, Bill, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bernstein, Steven J., 1981-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Bessy, Claude and Philomena, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Binet, Hervé, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Blair, David, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Blance, George, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Blanchard, Jim, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Block, Adam, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Blumb, Jon, 1990-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Boardman, Chris, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bob Callahan Studios, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bockris, Victor, 1982-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Böhlke, Rainer, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Borrero, Angel, 1986-1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Botz, Chris, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bourgois, Christian, 1982-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bowles, Paul, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bradshaw, David, 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Brandenburg, Bob, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Breger, Udo, 1982-2000 (Box 4, Folder 12-15, Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brookner, Howard, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Andreas, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bucher, François, 1983-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4-7)
  - Buchsteiner, Thomas, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Budd, David, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Buhler, Rosine
    - "The Galerie" -- Audio Recording, 1986 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0001)
    - Letters, 1985-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10-11, Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Bukowski, Charles, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bull, Hank, 1988-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Burroughs, Dorcas, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Burroughs, Miggy and Mortimer, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Butterworth, Michael, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Calder, John, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Campbell, Gordon, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Campbell, Mathilda -- Duchess of Argyll, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Carr, Lucien, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Carr, Virginia Spencer, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Castro, David Solero, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Chamberlain, John, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Chang, Jonathan, 1985-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Chapman, Harold, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Chapman, Lee, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Charters, Ann, 1986-1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Chase, Arthur, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Christopher, T.K., 1991 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Christopherson, Peter, 1979-1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Cleve, Gerhard Henri, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cohen, Ira, 1986-1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Community School -- St. Louis, 1988-1995 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Condo, George, 1988-1996 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Corleone, Michele, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Corso, Gregory, 1984-1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Cortez, Diego, 1984-1995 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Crockett, Tobey, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Cudlipp, William C., 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Dahlberg, Rlene, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - De Chadenèdes, John, David, and Audrey, 1982-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - De Palaminy, François (Fafa), 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Di Prima, Diane and Rudi, 1988-1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dillon, Richard, 1983-1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dozier, Bill, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Duke University Primate Center, 1986-1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Dunbar, Ian, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Duval, Jean-François -- Construire, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ellis, Simone, 1984-1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Elovich, Richard, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Elvins, Peter, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Ely, Roger, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Emerton, Michael, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Ewert, Mark, 1989-1997 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fabre, Gladys -- Galerie de France, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Faithfull, Marianne, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Fallowell, Duncan, 1983-1992 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Fass, David Harvard, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Featherstone, Edward, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Feinstein, Laura (Laura Lee), 1985-1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Féray, Serge, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Ferez, José, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fisher, Linda, 1982-1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Flaming Lips -- Wayne Coyne, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ford, Charles Henri, 1986-1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Forster, Christina L., 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Foundation for Shamanic Studies, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Fox, Carole, 1983-1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Foye, Raymond, 1982-1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - French, Piers, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Fulton, Robert, 1987-1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Gale, Robert (Possibly), undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - García-Robles, Jorge, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Gatewood, Charles, 1987-2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Geiger, John Grigsby, 1990-2001 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Gibson, William, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Gifford, Barry, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Ginsberg, Allen
    - Drawing -- "Paterson", 1992 (Box Shared Fales 122, Folder 11)
    - Letters and Press Clippings, 1963-1999 (Box 8, Folder 21-24)
  - Giorno, John, 1986-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Girodias, Maurice, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Goldberg, Jeff, 1982-1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Grady, Panna, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Grauerholz, James, 1981-1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gray, Kathelin, 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Green, Theo, 1982-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gridley, Karl, 1986-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Günter, Thomas, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Guy, Will, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gysin, Brion
    - Event Poster, 1982 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 9)
    - Letters and Writing, 1980-1994 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Hamri and Blanca Hamri, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hannah, Duncan, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Haring, Keith
    - Holiday Card, 1989 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 9)
    - Letters, Press Clippings, and Slides, 1986-1997 (Box 9, Folder 15-16, Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Harris, Oliver, 1985-1995 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hart, Grant, 1986-1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hayat, Yves, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Haynes, Jim, 1987-1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hebert, Caroline, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Heidsieck, Bernard, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Heliczer, Piero, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Helnwein, Gottfried and Renate, 1989-1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Herzeld, Barbara, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Heying, Phil, 1986-1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hockney, David, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hoffman, Abbie, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Holden, Roger, 1988-1996 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hopkins, John, 1989-1997 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hunke, Herbert, 1985-1996 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Iguchi, Kaori, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Illuminates of Thanateros, 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 18-19, Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ilsley, George K., 1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Indiana, Gary, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - International Coalition for Religious Freedom, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jaffe, Ira, 1984-1997 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Janicot, Françoise, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Jarrard, Kyle -- International Herald Tribune, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jenkins, James, 1987-1995 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Jessen, John -- Grove Weidenfeld, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, James, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Ray, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Kaplan, Mark, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Kennerly, Don, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Kennison, Don, 1990-1997 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Kerouac, Edie Parker
    - Fishing Map, circa 1980s (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 9)
    - Letters and Photograph, 1983-1993 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Kerouac, Jan, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Kesey, Ken, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Kimball, Diane, 1989-1995 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Knight, Kit and Arthur, 1986-1993 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Knoebber, Roger, 1990-1994 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Kohlhofer, Christof, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
  - Krassner, Paul, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Kush -- Cloud House Poetry Archives, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Lacina, Lawrence Damien, 1989-1992 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Lacy, Steve, 1986-1994 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Lagarde, François, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Laszlo, Carl, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Laughead, George, 1991-1997 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Lawrence Animal Shelter, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lazzeri, Simone, 1986-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Leary, Timothy, 1986-1996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Lemaire, Gerard-Georges, 1983-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Lenz, Brad, 1987-1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Editors, 1965-1976 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Levine, Les and Catherine, 1988-1993 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Levy, Bill, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Libertarian Party, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ljutic Industries, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - London, Rick, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Los Alamos Ranch School/Camp, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Lotringer, Sylvère, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lowe, Steve and Family, 1979-1997 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Lucas, Christopher, 1986-1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Lydenberg, Robin, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lyon, Bill, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lyon, Randall, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Mackenzie, David, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Maeck, Klaus, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Magruder, Klaus, 1980-1996 (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1993-1996 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Malanga, Gerard, 1993-1997 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Manley, Roger, 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Marlowe, Alan and Kreg Thornley, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Marsh, Dave, 1994-1997 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Marshall, Steve, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Mason, Felicity, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 29, Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Matta, Ramuntcho, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Maynard, Joe, 1983-1997 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - McCann, James Kennedy, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - McCarthy, Mary, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - McClure, Michael, 1986-1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - McCrary, James, 1985-2012 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - McLean, Cabell, 1982-1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - McMaster, John, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - McNeil, Legs, 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Meyer, Stewart, 1982-1997 (Box 13, Folder 11-13)
  - Meyers, Richard (a.k.a. Richard Hell), 1997 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Myers, John, 1988-1994 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Mikriammos, Phillip, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Miles, Barry, 1987-1997 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Mitzel, Frank, 1983-1986 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Montgomery, John, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Moore, Bob -- Locust Press, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Moran, Timothy, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Morgan, Ted, 1985-1995 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Morrow, Brad, 1986-1992 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Mottram, Eric, 1987-1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Naked Lunch Productions, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Naropa Institute, 1976-1985 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Neiss, James, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Nestle, David Crowbar -- Popular Reality, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Nicocia, Gerard, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Norse, Harold, 1985-1993 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Nutting, Cherie and Bachir Atar, 1990-1997 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ohle, David, 1984-1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Olmsted, Marc, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - O'Neal, Hank, 1985-1993 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Page, Tim -- Modern Painters, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Papademos, Basil, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Partouche, Marc, Rosine Buhler, et al. -- Collaborative Art Book, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Pattison, Charlotte P., 1993 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Pelieu, Claude and Mary Beach, 1982-1994 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - PEN American Center, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Perrizo, Jim, 1989-1993 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Peschio, Tom, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Petrich, Jeff, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Pini, Massimo, 1982-1992 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Plimpton, George, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Ploog, Jürgen, 1986-1997 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Plymell, Charles, 1982-1996 (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
  - Pollett, Ron, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - P-Orridge, Genesis, 1973-1993 (Box 14, Folder 27-28)
  - Possett, Benn, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Pounds, Wayne, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Prentice, David, 1982-1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Price, Vincent, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Probst, Wayne
    - Artwork, circa 1989-1997 (Flat-file-folder Temp 001)
    - Letters, 1986-1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pursel, Richard, 1993
    - Drawing Studies of Burroughs (Box Shared Fales 122, Folder 11)
    - Letters (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Quick, David Lee, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Resnick, Martha, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Rich, Bill, 1980-1994 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Richards, Roger, 1989-1995 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Riches, Pierre, 1985-1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Ripa, Dean, 1984-1999 (Box 15, Folder 12-17, Box 16, Folder 1-6)